<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>SharePoint on The State of the Microsoft 365 Nation</title>
        <link>https://www.menzel.it/categories/sharepoint/</link>
        <description>Recent content in SharePoint on The State of the Microsoft 365 Nation</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 20:19:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.menzel.it/categories/sharepoint/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>External User Access Reviews in Office 365</title>
        <link>https://www.menzel.it/post/2023/11/external-user-access-reviews-office-365-ensuring-secure-collaboration/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 20:19:16 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://www.menzel.it/post/2023/11/external-user-access-reviews-office-365-ensuring-secure-collaboration/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://www.menzel.it/post/2023/11/external-user-access-reviews-office-365-ensuring-secure-collaboration/HeaderImage.png" alt="Featured image of post External User Access Reviews in Office 365" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding External User Access&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving into the reviews, it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand what external access entails. External users in O365 are individuals who are not employees, or onsite agents for your organization. They could be partners, vendors, or consultants who need access to certain parts of your O365 environment, such as SharePoint sites or Microsoft Teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Need for Access Reviews&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principle of least privilege mandates that users should have access only to the information and resources that are absolutely necessary for their work. Over time, access requirements can change, and periodic reviews ensure that external users only have the access they need. This is where O365&amp;rsquo;s access review feature comes into play, allowing for the systematic verification and auditing of user privileges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting Up Access Reviews&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To set up access reviews in O365, follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Navigate to the Access Reviews Dashboard&lt;/strong&gt;: Access this via the Microsoft 365 compliance center or Azure Active Directory (EntraID) portal.




&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.menzel.it/post/2023/11/external-user-access-reviews-office-365-ensuring-secure-collaboration/image.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width: 50%; display: block;&#34;&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a New Access Review&lt;/strong&gt;: Specify the scope of the review, whether it&amp;rsquo;s targeted at guest users across all Microsoft Teams and Groups or specific ones.




&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.menzel.it/post/2023/11/external-user-access-reviews-office-365-ensuring-secure-collaboration/image-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width: 50%; display: block;&#34;&gt;






&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.menzel.it/post/2023/11/external-user-access-reviews-office-365-ensuring-secure-collaboration/image-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width: 50%; display: block;&#34;&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Define Review Settings&lt;/strong&gt;: Choose who will perform the review (group owners, specific users, or application owners), set the frequency (one-time or recurring), and establish the start and end dates.




&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.menzel.it/post/2023/11/external-user-access-reviews-office-365-ensuring-secure-collaboration/image-3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width: 50%; display: block;&#34;&gt;






&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.menzel.it/post/2023/11/external-user-access-reviews-office-365-ensuring-secure-collaboration/image-4.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width: 50%; display: block;&#34;&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customize Review Settings&lt;/strong&gt;: Decide on the outcomes for denied access, such as automatic removal or a manual step, and whether reviewers receive reminders.




&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.menzel.it/post/2023/11/external-user-access-reviews-office-365-ensuring-secure-collaboration/image-5.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width: 50%; display: block;&#34;&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Review and Confirm&lt;/strong&gt;: Double-check the settings, and then create the access review.




&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.menzel.it/post/2023/11/external-user-access-reviews-office-365-ensuring-secure-collaboration/image-6.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width: 50%; display: block;&#34;&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conducting the Review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once set up, designated reviewers will be notified to examine the access rights of external users. Reviewers can approve or deny access for each user, and they can provide reasons for their decisions. It&amp;rsquo;s best practice to include guidelines for making these decisions to ensure consistency and compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Examples of Access Reviews in Action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vendor Access Review&lt;/strong&gt;: A company conducts quarterly reviews of vendor access to its internal procurement system to validate that only current vendors have access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consultant Project Completion&lt;/strong&gt;: Upon the completion of a project, the external consultant’s access to the project’s SharePoint site is reviewed and revoked if no longer needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Partner Collaboration&lt;/strong&gt;: Annual reviews of a partner organization’s access to shared Teams channels are performed to ensure that only relevant individuals retain access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Practices&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regular Schedule&lt;/strong&gt;: Conduct access reviews on a regular schedule to maintain security hygiene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clear Documentation&lt;/strong&gt;: Keep detailed records of each review for auditing purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User Notification&lt;/strong&gt;: Inform external users about the review process to ensure transparency and avoid confusion if access is altered or revoked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access reviews in O365 are an essential practice for maintaining secure and efficient collaborations with external users. By regularly reviewing and adjusting access rights, organizations can protect sensitive information while facilitating productive partnerships. With O365’s robust access review tools, you can ensure that your external collaborations are both productive and secure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>New Image Editing Options in SharePoint Online: A Deep Dive into the Image Web Part</title>
        <link>https://www.menzel.it/post/2023/11/spimageediting/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 13:19:06 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://www.menzel.it/post/2023/11/spimageediting/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://www.menzel.it/post/2023/11/spimageediting/HeaderImage.png" alt="Featured image of post New Image Editing Options in SharePoint Online: A Deep Dive into the Image Web Part" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;adding-and-editing-images-with-the-image-web-part&#34;&gt;Adding and Editing Images with the Image Web Part&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Image web part simplifies the process of adding visual elements to your SharePoint Online pages. Here&amp;rsquo;s how you can set it up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;inserting-an-image&#34;&gt;Inserting an Image&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigate to the page where you want to add an image and select &amp;ldquo;Edit&amp;rdquo; at the top right of the page to enable editing mode. Choose the section you want to insert the Image web part and click the &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; sign to add a new web part. Select &amp;ldquo;Image&amp;rdquo; from the list of available web parts.




&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.menzel.it/post/2023/11/spimageediting/SCR-20231110-owfe.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width: 40%; display: block;&#34;&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;editing-an-image&#34;&gt;Editing an Image&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the image is inserted, you might want to fine-tune its appearance. Click the &amp;lsquo;Advanced editing&amp;rsquo; to access the editing options. From there, you can:




&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.menzel.it/post/2023/11/spimageediting/SCR-20231110-oxpo.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width: 40%; display: block;&#34;&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crop:&lt;/strong&gt; Adjust the framing of your image to focus on the most important elements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adjustment:&lt;/strong&gt; Modify brightness, contrast, and saturation to ensure your image stands out or blends in with the overall design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Filters:&lt;/strong&gt; Apply filters for artistic effects or to conform to your branding guidelines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markup:&lt;/strong&gt; Add shapes, lines, and text to your image to highlight specific elements.

    
    
    
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.menzel.it/post/2023/11/spimageediting/SCR-20231110-oycy.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width: 70%; display: block;&#34;&gt;
    
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;adding-text-overlays&#34;&gt;Adding Text Overlays&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enhance your images by adding text directly over them. While in the edit mode of the Image web part, you&amp;rsquo;ll find an option to &amp;ldquo;add text over the image.&amp;rdquo; Click on it, and a text box will appear on your image where you can enter your desired text. This feature is particularly useful for headers, announcements, or to convey additional context.




&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.menzel.it/post/2023/11/spimageediting/SCR-20231110-oysu.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width: 40%; display: block;&#34;&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;configuring-accessibility&#34;&gt;Configuring Accessibility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s crucial to ensure that your images are accessible to all users. When editing the Image web part, add descriptive alternative text that accurately represents the image content for users who use screen readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;saving-your-edits&#34;&gt;Saving Your Edits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After making all your edits, don&amp;rsquo;t forget to save your changes. You can publish or republish the page to make the changes live or you can &amp;lsquo;Save as draft&amp;rsquo; to work on this page later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Image web part in SharePoint Online is a powerful tool that, with its new editing capabilities, can significantly enhance the visual impact of your pages. By following these detailed steps, you can effectively use images to complement your textual content, make your pages more engaging, and ensure they are inclusive for all users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
